<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>Cyberpark Nichome • Posts by &#34;ameitsu orchestra&#34; tag</title>
        <link>https://ameitsu.github.io</link>
        <description>本站部分内容来自一个在某只不愿透露姓名的猫娘上的脑机接口。没有任何猫娘因为本站而受到伤害。</description>
        <language>zh-CN</language>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:38:02 +0800</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:38:02 +0800</lastBuildDate>
        <category>at STY</category>
        <category>原创</category>
        <category>高中牲STY-番外</category>
        <category>STY的初三大事记</category>
        <category>高中牲STY</category>
        <category>Notorial</category>
        <category>SofTY</category>
        <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
        <category>水水水</category>
        <category>铁路</category>
        <category>冷门铁路史系列</category>
        <category>非原创</category>
        <category>多图杀猫</category>
        <category>站庆</category>
        <category>重要页面</category>
        <category>学习</category>
        <category>游记</category>
        <category>实践活动</category>
        <category>站内页面</category>
        <category>Python</category>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-9/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.9 | 说预判</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-9/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>高中牲STY</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 19:38:02 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是 STY 在语文课上现写的小东西，一下就整了个 39，相对来说比之前好多啦喵！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 1&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;近年来 “预判” 一词的出现频率愈发增加，小到学生对学习目标和人生的计划，大至国家的五年规划的制订与环境变化的预测，可见无论对个人、社会或是国家，随波逐流并非明智之举，唯有审时度势的预判才是正道。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 2&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;预判是根据当下规律性的情况，对未来的趋势的判断。它区别于猜测与推知：未来的局面尚不可知，而影响未来的线索又纷繁复杂，又不同于的解题。而对于一个合理又精准的预判、远景、宏观性和应变是不可或缺的元素。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 3&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;预判有了前瞻性，才能让人跳出面前的局势或境况、判断未来。上世纪六七十年代的中国一穷二白，国家却也发展核工业，这正是一种高瞻远瞩：“两弹一星” 的成功使中国后来成为独立自主的泱泱大国带来可能。面对 2008 年的金融危机，雷军并未拘泥于困境中，而是大胆预测了未来移动互联网产业的崛起，这才有了小米公司。预判，必须有前瞻的视野，倘不依发展之 “预”，谋长远之 “判”，怎能顺应时代之潮？&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 4&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;有了高瞻远瞩，便能使预判生效，同时全局性也应体现在预判之中。计算机中央处理器分配线程内存，需要预判整台设备的需求；国家推行 “五位一体” 的规划，也是出于对经济、社会，生态等角度做出的综合预测。倘若计算机只预测部分设备的情况，国家只顾经济高速发展，造成的资源浪费只会愈发严重。这充分说明即使情况纷繁复杂，顾及全局的预判也是正道。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 5&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;除此之外，灵活性的预判有助于提高预判的精准性。皇佑二年，杭州饥荒，新上任的州长官范仲淹面对灾情时并没有死板地下令开仓放粮，而是综合评判了浙江当时的情况：浙江余粮甚多，而大多囤积在富人和寺庙手中，缺乏流通；放粮会引起这些人的反感而使赈灾无法正常进行。因此，他预判到大幅度提高物价以吸引粮商运粮至杭州可平衡供需关系，让粮价自然回落，又不引起矛盾，这正也是范仲淹最终成功的破局之策。人们往往局限在由过去经验构筑的条条框框中，而灵活变通地寻求破局之策才有可能使预判精准命中问题之眼。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 6&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;预判，要求前瞻性，全局性与灵活性有机结合：不前瞻则丧失预判的根基，不全局则局限格局眼界，不灵活则易陷入死局而不知，利用前瞻性预判未来变化之方向，运用全局性预判整体性的局面，活用灵活性预判变化的变化，才能远离目光短浅的困境、繁杂混乱的乱境、捉襟见肘的窘境。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 7&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;总而言之，预判的重要性不言而喻，而预判也要求前瞻性，全局性和灵活性三位一体。正处于世界未有之大变局和科技赋能社会之现状的我们更应做到这三点，为人生谋篇布局，开未来之正路。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://utteranc.es/client.js&#34;
        repo=&#34;ameitsu/ameitsu.github.io&#34;
        issue-term=&#34;title&#34;
        label=&#34;Comments&#34;
        theme=&#34;github-light&#34;
        crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;
        async&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-8/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.8 | Scott of Antarctica</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-8/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 19:38:02 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这依然是某一次的英语作业。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;scott-of-antarctica-the-ill-fated-warrior-against-nature&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#scott-of-antarctica-the-ill-fated-warrior-against-nature&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Scott of Antarctica: The ill-fated warrior against nature&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A year-round Antarctic station became fully operational in November 1956, and occupying the southernmost point of the place where we stand since the furthest history: the south pole. Though Constructed by US National Science Foundation, the station wasn’t named using any great American figure’s name, instead they used two literally immortal names of humanity: Amundsen and Scott.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-two-warriors&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#the-two-warriors&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; The two warriors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two men were both explorers, whose expertise were searching the frontier of the Earth. Amundsen was the first human to reach the south pole, and  certainly he looked like the perfect person ever to accomplish this epic mission, since he had just navigated the icy waters of Canadian Northwest and Yukon. He seemed so well-prepared and fortunate, therefore people often focus on the deceased loser of the race to the south pole —— Captain Scott.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;scotts-voyage&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#scotts-voyage&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Scott&#39;s voyage&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Subsequent to Scott’s death, Amundsen mourned him and commented that Scott was the embodiment of all great characters of humans. Scott is famed for his unsuccessful expedition to the pole, and there is certainly a reason for it. Scott’s team encountered mechanical failures of their motorized sledges right after their departure, and facing challenges when you have just started is never better than failing it completely. After marching in the icy Antarctic plateaus in low mood for two months, they witnessed the scenario that none of the teammates would imagine: Amundsen arrived with a Norwegian flag already. This accounted for the second punch on their ambitions. The true despair occurred on their way back. With days passing by, the men soon realized the frightening fact that all supplies were in shortage. The explorers gradually slowed down the progress and eventually watched how fellow teammates die before them. And finally, the finale: Scott spent the final hours of himself to write the one last letter to his loved wife and son.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-can-we-say&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-can-we-say&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; What can we say&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since his death, opinions claiming Scott’s crude decision-making ability accounted for the tragedy were widely spread. Undoubtedly, it is a truth: Scott decided to use Yakut ponies and powered sledges rather than the safest option of skis and dogs, despite being warned by Amundsen prior to his departure. Nevertheless, he still deserved the title as the hero of Antarctica. The thing that powered Scott within was the spirit of endeavor and self-sacrificing. Regardless of the miserable beginning, the team managed to reach the destination. This is a character shared by all explorers from Christopher Columbus in the Atlantic to Neil Armstrong and Buzz Aldrin up on the moon. Nothing burdensome could be accomplished without endeavor, not to mention traversing Antarctica. Soon after the men became aware about their destiny, they kept on and collected a total of 20 kilograms of precious stones that could possibly prove Antarctica’s geological history as a vibrant world rather than a snowy wasteland, saving considerable time and efforts for succeeding researchers. Resigning to their fate, the last two men, including Scott, breathed their final breath in a blizzard of 1912, yet they have already achieved more than attempting to reach the south pole: Not just researched Antarctica, but also explored the limit of human beings’ might. Failing never meant an unfortunate conclusion, those failed on their pathway of pursuing a greater good are the ones that ignited the flame of hope to guide the rest. And that is exactly the story of captain Robert Falcon Scott, the martyr on human’s way of conquering unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://utteranc.es/client.js&#34;
        repo=&#34;ameitsu/ameitsu.github.io&#34;
        issue-term=&#34;title&#34;
        label=&#34;Comments&#34;
        theme=&#34;github-light&#34;
        crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;
        async&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-7/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.7 | 一个给叶■陶杯写的东西</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-7/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 11:38:03 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STY 的语文老师要求实验班所有人都得写一个，而且是在开学第一周啊！气 fufu。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;雨儿胡同的故人&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#雨儿胡同的故人&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 雨儿胡同的故人&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#1&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 1&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;北京是一个 “盛产” 名人故居的城市。在内城的一些犄角旮旯里你总能与某个有名的老邻居不期而遇，在这雨儿胡同里也一样。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#2&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 2&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;院子虽不起眼，但其主人却是中国艺术史上殿堂级的人物 —— 齐白石；巷道虽不出名，但不远却是老城最繁华的街道之一 —— 南锣鼓巷，院内的狭小和静谧与南锣鼓巷似乎不在同一时空中：南锣鼓巷里网红店里人头攒动，人流熙熙攘攘；而院里只有白墙灰瓦的呢喃和岁月侵蚀的刻痕，如同史书一般，寂静的仿佛停滞在那位艺术家仍健在的时光。&lt;br /&gt;
齐白石旧居是一座三合院 —— 甚至比巷子里的许多院落少一 “合”。一进院落，再穿入内门，就来到了旧居的核心 —— 袖珍而简朴。旧居也几乎保留着时光的倒影，一切都像齐白石老人才刚出门一般真实且生动。从窗棂上斜射几束阳光，随意抚摸着展台上摊开的卷轴，定睛一看，是那些活在齐白石老人轶事中的那些虾。再回头望向屋内，赭石色的齐白石雕像恍忽间似刚起身。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#3&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 3&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;齐白石老人身上有一些难以忽视的标签：飘乎世外，似乎不属于二十世纪，齐白石在镜头前几乎都是这一身行头：深蓝长袍马褂，金丝圆框眼镜，即便在建国后也如此，堪比行走的历史照片。老人的创作也几乎从未打断，甚至在兵荒马乱的年代里他产出了最巅峰的作品。人们道听途说抑或是孩子们从课本上阅读到的轶事，也几乎都是关于那些名作的诞生，鲜少有关于他起居生活的故事，似乎齐白石就是他手中的那杆毛笔的化身。身为人民艺术家的齐白石有如此超乎普通人的气质，更让这间平平无奇的三合小院更加与众不同。&lt;br /&gt;
一个人的事业体现一个人的气质，而超脱世俗的齐白石也是其艺术所成就的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#4&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 4&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;齐白石是人民艺术家的一员，也常以古稀老者的形象闻名于世，俨然一副国画大家的面貌。这尽管是不可争认的事实，但人们在脑海中浮现出的国画家形象往往是不苟言笑、性格古怪、故作高深的，而齐白石则是例外，齐白石画作的浓厚乡土气息，天真浪漫的童心富有余味的诗意，构成了作品的内在生命与齐白石的精神内核。而那热烈明快的色彩，墨与色的强烈对比，浑拙的造型和笔法、工与写的极端，则是作品的外在生命与齐白石刚中有柔的老者形象的体现。这二者的合璧，既构成了齐白石的艺术生涯，更有他的人生。艺术意味着呼唤人性中最初的美好，由人的本能，即从对美的认识出发感知世界，这正是成就齐白石和他能流芳千古的原因。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;5&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#5&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 5&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;能与时代的精神统一得完美无暇，这是齐白石在中国画上难能可贵的功绩。他既赋予作品童真与质朴清新的农民情感，也赋予文人画以现代性与生命力。从他对画虾的琢磨，到开创 “红花墨叶” 的大写意风格，他所做的正是拉近 “文雅” 与 “世俗”，赋予中国画全新的活力，发展中国画的创造性画法与面向广大人民的创作使其真正成为一名人民艺术家，与那个时代生机蓬勃的精神共鸣。同时齐白石在抗战中坚守作画的原则，拒绝向侵略者卖画，而在抗美援朝义卖上他却捐出大量画作，他与时代精神的共振也不言而喻。艺术不仅是个人精神的辐射，更是与时代精神相统一甚至是构建时代精神本身的途径。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;6&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#6&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 6&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;爱与和平，也是这位大家的作品中时常做客的主题。《百花与和平鸽》《和平胜利》《和平万岁》《和平颂》…… 一个个 “和平” 虽然的确受到抗战、解放战争乃至冷战的影响，但能如此热爱世界的大同，齐白石老人的确有过人之处。在当时的时代背景下，能对和平抱有如此大的热情，除了齐白石老人自身心系全人类，更少不了他的艺术对他的潜移默化。还是 “红花墨叶”，花开叶生在红与黑的极致对撞中尽显无留；还是他的虾，似柔实刚、乱中有序，自然界的奇迹之一，生命的挥洒，被展现得淋漓尽致。艺术使人回归到那些纯真的美好中，感受这个充满奇迹的世界，感受到作为人类能观察到这一切是多么幸运…… 于是争端和战争就显得冗余了。艺术是将个人的精神与全人类的共同精神相结合的过程，正如齐白石在充满童真和乡土气息的作品中追求人们自古以来共同向往的和平。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;7&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#7&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 7&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;于是，就有了这么一位传奇的国画大师。在逝世近七十年后，他的故事依然活在道听途说的故事中，活在课本的文章中，刻在几处纪念堂和故居中，依然被大人和孩子们所知。也许被人铭记本身就是成就，但齐白石身上有着一些比这些都值得留念的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;8&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#8&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 8&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;所以我们又回到了艺术上。至今依然有人追求艺术 —— 也许齐白石老人也对这感到满意，但艺术在一些人群中逐渐向一种花瓶般的摆设演进：考取了演奏某种乐器的等级证书，只是为了综合素质评价上 “特长” 一栏能多出几句话，甚至这件乐器在平时都鲜少拿起；去了美术馆，只是为了一张 “宣传照”，显得自己的情操是如此的超乎大众…… 这时齐白石老人就能成为当代的一个榜样了。艺术从来不是一项展示自己的成就，而是为了发掘人性最初的美好，是建设美好社会的责任，更是将个人的精神世界与全人类的相结合的过程。除此之外，生活中的艺术似乎也在褪色：固然有大量艺术作品的产出，但在信息化时代它们又被淹没在无尽的数据流中；音乐和美术科目总被占，这是一个不争的尴尬事实…… 确实有理由解释，但艺术作为人类本能的延伸，需要占据生活的一席之地。齐白石老人的虾，他的花，使他领略自然的美好，从而心胸愈发宽广…… 这正是艺术的力量的体现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;9&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#9&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 9&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;现在看来，纪念齐白石这位雨儿胡同的故人，更是纪念艺术本身，呼唤艺术在某种程度上的重归。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;10&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#10&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 10&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;夜幕降临，行人逐渐减少，雨儿胡同也逐渐平静下来。离巷口不远的地方，一座三合院的灯火依然通明，如同那个曾经住过的故人在艺术上发出的光芒。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://utteranc.es/client.js&#34;
        repo=&#34;ameitsu/ameitsu.github.io&#34;
        issue-term=&#34;title&#34;
        label=&#34;Comments&#34;
        theme=&#34;github-light&#34;
        crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;
        async&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/uncategorized/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-6/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.5| STY奇文共赏之锐评■京地铁</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/uncategorized/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-6/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 22:42:07 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;但凡多看几篇您就会知道咱这儿的 &lt;strong&gt;“■京”&lt;/strong&gt; 实为中国北京市。原则上所有的 “北京” 都得替换成 “■京”，但这篇是&lt;strong&gt;唯一的例外&lt;/strong&gt;。蟹蟹。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note default&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这是 STY 的寒假地理作业之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;新的阶段新的布局一个研究性学习&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#新的阶段新的布局一个研究性学习&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 新的阶段，新的布局：一个研究性学习&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;—— 从地理必修二的内容分析北京地铁新线对区域发展的影响&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;一引入&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#一引入&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 一．	引入&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;每年的十二月底，有一些值得期待的事情在北京发生：圣诞节、跨年、元旦假期…… 还有一个 “保留节目” 是北京地铁开通几条新线路或车站。自从 2016 年最后一天 16 号线北段开通以来，北京的地铁网络密度显著提升，同时此后开通的其他线路也具有显著的共性与和既有线的明显差别。这些新的变化既显现北京地铁的全新布局思路，更有利于北京的区域发展，尤其是南北向的沟通。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;高中地理教材必修二第四章介绍了一些交通运输布局的原则、区域发展和交通运输布局的互相影响等内容。我们可以从这些角度出发，分析新线路的布局和设备等特点如何优化了北京交通网络的布局与城区协调发展。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;二北京地铁新线的特点和区域交通布局的原则&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#二北京地铁新线的特点和区域交通布局的原则&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 二．	北京地铁新线的特点和区域交通布局的原则&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;此处提到的北京地铁新线，指的是 16、17、19 号线。不难得出这三条线具有如下七个共性：&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;站距较大：三条线平均站距分别为 1.71、2.87、2.32 千米，高于大部分线路的平均站距。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;运营速度较快：列车最高速度在 80-100 千米每小时之间，显著高于其他列车。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;南北走向：16 号线从西北方向的北安河延伸到西南方向的宛平城，17 号线从偏东北的未来科学城延伸到东南的亦庄，19 号线从牡丹园纵贯北京核心区到新宫。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;全地下线：三条线的每一座车站均位于地下，中途无地面或高架部分。车辆段全封闭或有上盖，轨道上方一直有建筑物遮盖，也可视为地下。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;车辆载客量大：三条线的车辆都是 8A 编组。从车厢数上说，这高于其他线路 6 节车厢的配置；从宽度上看，A 车厢的宽度大于 B 车厢，即载客量更大。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;沿途交通枢纽多：16 号线上的国家图书馆站、17 号线的十里河站、19 号线的草桥站等均为三条线路交汇的大站，同时 16 号线在北京丰台站设站、19 号线在新宫接驳大兴机场线。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;连接新开发地区：丽泽商务区、经开区、海淀后山等新区位于三条线附近。&lt;br /&gt;
而根据必修二教材，交通网络的布局应满足这五条原则：&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;条件制约：既有技术装备和经济发展条件，也有地质等自然条件。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;运输需求：不仅是目前的交通运输实际，也需要满足未来可能的需求或者说适度超前建设。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;节约土地：站点和线路应尽量少占用土地，尤其是耕地。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;综合体系：和不同交通运输方式衔接，形成立体的交通运输网络。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;平衡区域：连接新开发地区或欠开发地区到市中心，拉近这些地区与城市中心区的经济发展差距。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;三北京地铁新线如何落实这些原则&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#三北京地铁新线如何落实这些原则&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 三．	北京地铁新线如何落实这些原则&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;前文提到的五个原则在北京地铁的三条新线上得到了体现。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在技术层面，三条新线采用了全新的 DKZ93 和 CCD5034 等 8A 编组列车与自动化技术。增大的车厢与增加的车长势必会大幅提高单列车的载客量与运输效率。以 DKZ93 为例，该车型单列车载客量为 2480 人，而 6B 编组的 DKZ13 载客量却仅有 1424 人。17 和 19 号线均为自动线路，自动化控制的线路使车辆调度更加灵敏，能做到在高峰期时压缩发车间隔，优化高峰期运行效率。总的来说，全新的装备增大运输效率，对跨区域尤其是长距离运输更加有针对性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;交通运输需求在这三条线上也得到了满足。从目前建成区间来看，16 号线服务于西部地区，覆盖此前仅有 4 号线途经的海淀后山与最近几年才开工建设的丽泽商务区，而这些地区因此前缺少地铁线路而有较大的交通运输需求。17 号线虽然目前分南北段开通，但两段均有 “热点” 地区：北段，工人体育场作为体育赛事和文艺活动承办场所是重要的目的地；南端，位于亦庄的站点是新的通勤起始点，服务于经开区。19 号线的作用之一，就是填补了先前大兴机场线只到草桥的遗憾，满足中心城区和北部城区居民前往南部大兴机场的需求。可见，三条线路都满足了特定的交通运输需求。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;鉴于三条线均为地下线路，大量土地资源得以保留。地面和高架线路的车站规模虽然小于地下线路，但鉴于地面和高架车站和线路之外需要设置隔离区，实际上占用的地面空间仍大于地下线路，因为地下线路占用的土地资源仅为若干个出入口的部分。这三条线路服务于开发区，因此地下线路节约土地资源的特点更是其优势。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;三条线路的部分枢纽站使不同线路或交通方式得到了较好的结合。最明显的是，北京地铁全路网三线换乘站 8 个中有 4 个位于这三条线上，路网结构得到改善，客流纾解更容易，因为乘客可前往的方向增多。16 号线上的丰台站使乘客可通过地铁系统抵达周边无快速路、交通相对不便的丰台站；17 号线附近有亦庄 T1 有轨电车，也和亦庄线接驳，在远期亦庄火车站如果开通，则能连接京津城际，促进亦庄内外部交通发展；19 号线在草桥站接驳大兴机场线，而大兴机场线的目的地更是不言而喻。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最后，三条线路做到了平衡区域发展。16 号线将海淀山后、三里河行政中心区、北京丰台站、北京丽泽金融商务区、丰台科技园等重要城市功能区相连；17 号线加强经开区和未来科学城与主城区的联系；19 号线通过与大兴机场线协调，为大兴机场和空港开发区与城区的连接提供交通保障。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;四新的变化如何作用于北京区域发展&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#四新的变化如何作用于北京区域发展&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 四．	新的变化如何作用于北京区域发展&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;既然要平衡区域发展，那么有区域间的连接、在有需要的区域之间连接、有快速高效的连接是需要的。&lt;br /&gt;
首先，在形成连接方面，三条线路均在若干城区外围开发区和居民区与城市核心区间形成运输通道。之所以强调单独的形成连接，是因为在既有交通设施上开设线路没有使用全新独立交通设施的交通方式运行效率高，而运输效率是促进区域发展中人员流动的重要因素。&lt;br /&gt;
其次，就是连接区域的选择。16 号线上既有海淀后山地区这样的轨道交通交通欠发达地区，也有丽泽商务区等新开发区，当然还经过主城区的金融街附近，这些地区都具有重要发展潜力和交通需求，16 号线通过满足交通需求有助于挖掘这些潜力。17 和 19 号线都经过先前是一片 “空白” 的南部新城，对于拉进这些新城区与城市核心区的作用更加显而易见。通过将有需求有潜力的地区和城区连接，区域发展能进一步平衡。&lt;br /&gt;
最后和最主要的是运输效率。车辆选择、运行方式和接驳线路都是决定运输效率的重要因素，而三条新线兼顾了这三点。在车辆上，三条线路均使用 8A 编组，提高近千人的载客量；在运行方式上，三条线路的列车采用较高的速度运行，同时 17 和 19 号线采取自动驾驶模式，更易调度；在接驳线路上，三条线路均有大型的三线换乘站，16 号线与国家铁路接驳，17 号线与城区局部的有轨电车联运，19 号线通过机场联络线可与机场相连。更高的速度，更大的载客量，更灵活的控制使线路自身的运输效率得以提高，而更多的换乘站和多元化的交通方式结合促进客流的疏导。运输效率提高，自然使人员进出新区更加容易。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;五展望&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#五展望&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 五．	展望&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;北京地铁的 16、17、19 三条新线说明北京地铁面对未来北京区域发展做出了改变：从小站距改为大站距，甚至出现 “交而不换” 的现象，通过减少停靠增快运营速度；改用大容量高速度的列车，适应新区发展的通勤需求；完善南北走向大型干线，平衡北部城区与南部新城和城市核心区的发展；形成交通枢纽分散分布的格局。而这些改变对于平衡区域发展，促进区域间人员流通，及时纾解客流也是至关重要的。&lt;br /&gt;
随着北京地铁新一轮建设的进行，平衡区域发展作为北京地铁的重要作用将促使更多类似 16、17、19 号线的大型快速干线出现，拉近区域间的连接。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;script src=&#34;https://utteranc.es/client.js&#34;
        repo=&#34;ameitsu/ameitsu.github.io&#34;
        issue-term=&#34;title&#34;
        label=&#34;Comments&#34;
        theme=&#34;github-light&#34;
        crossorigin=&#34;anonymous&#34;
        async&gt;
&lt;/script&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-4/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.4 | STY奇文共赏之高一上学期的上学期</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-4/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2023 19:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STY 决定要把自己在课上写过的破东西发出来丢人现眼一下。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;突围&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#突围&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 突围&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;人类的历史就是人类突破层层限制的斗争史。在这部人类破除对未知自然的恐惧、联系大陆之间彼此、革新观念和生产力的史诗中，作为笔墨的正是我们突围的努力。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;突围是指人发挥主观能动性，突破眼前困难与局限，从而开辟全新天地的过程。虽然人们往往着眼于为了突围而做出的措施，然而对突围起到更加决定性作用的是一以贯之的努力：没有恒定的目标引领、没有坚持突围的信心、没有持续发力的努力，任何方法都会付诸东流。突围，需要一以贯之。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;突围要破除层层困境，一以贯之的目标是必须的。如今，“天问一号” 的成功人尽皆知，而鲜为人知的是，在天问一号 10 年前，一次完全失败的火星探测任务 ——“萤火一号”—— 使地面上的中国团队意识到确定一个明确的火星探索以及突破运载火箭等瓶颈技术的目标有多么重要，“绕、落、巡” 三步走的火星探测计划也因此应运而生。在一以贯之的技术目标引领下，10 年后的天问一号终于冲出地月系的束缚，开启了深空探测之路。由此可见，一以贯之的目标是拨开困难迷雾的航向标。在层层困难前，唯有坚定的目标才能使突围成功。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;突围的路途难免曲折，一以贯之的信念是必要的。C919 客机背后的一位 “大国工匠”，胡双钱，三十多年来坚守让祖国飞机翱翔蓝天的信念，做到了上千万个零件无差错的奇迹，既让一位技工的事业实现了 “突围”，也让国家在航空领域成功 “突围”，走向国产化；宁允展，一位坚信产品质量必须完美才能履行工人职责、二十余年专攻列车转向架并做到十年无次品的工人，为 CRH380A 型高铁能驰骋祖国大地做出了至关重要的贡献。试想，如果这些 “大国工匠” 心中没有数十年坚持力求产品完美的信念和凭借自身工作满足国家和人民期待的觉悟，国家的发展又如何推进？正因为他们有如此的信念，而且从未改变，这些奇迹才能成真。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;突围总需要挑战极限，一以贯之的坚持是必然的。突围本身就是挑战困难与极限的过程，怎能瞬间而成？为突破大气层的束缚，人类自 1903 年液体火箭雏形提出后通过六十年的创新，才使第一位宇航员升空；人类基因测序从 1990 年开始，历经三十余年的探索，历经数次生物技术极限的突破，在 2022 年终获成果…… 极限是在曾经一次次尝试中设下的，因此只有坚持尝试才能将极限破除。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;突围之路上，除了怀揣突围的能力，更需要的是一以贯之的精神：一以贯之的目标、信念和坚持。只有一以贯之，才能使破除困境的能力得到真正体现，从而突围。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;弄潮&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#弄潮&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 弄潮&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;弄潮，即 “踏浪翻波”，意为在水中搏击、嬉戏。但它有着更深层次的意义，这也是今年来这个词语高频率出现的原因之一。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;弄潮，势必要在风险困难中拼搏。但若是成功消除了面前的 “巨浪”，自身体魄定会加强，眼前所见乃全新的景色。由此观之，获得超越和进步，是弄潮的意义所在。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;个人的弄潮，促进个人理想的实现，带来人生境界的提升。风险重重的基建事业中，涌现出一个个弄潮者：顾延安，冒着沉管隧道破裂的风险亲自检查港珠澳大桥的隧道；宁允展，顶着一丝误差即引起高铁脱轨的危险在十年间专造转向架…… 无数的大国工匠们与各自的风浪搏斗着，成为一个个不计回报的弄潮儿。除了实现使本职工作臻于完美的理想以外，他们更成就了国家的发展，将个人与国家民族命运相关联，人生的意义得到升华。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;社会的弄潮，促进多方合力的形成，带来社会面貌的巨变。中国举办各种赛事的历史，就是最好的体现：中国第一次亚运会，加快了包括北京在内众多城市的建设；中国第一次奥运会，革新了中国在新世纪的面貌…… 之所以仅仅一次盛会就能产生如此强大的力量，是因为人们鼎力支持，人人愿做 “弄潮儿”，冒着组织上抑或是技术上的风险投身于赛事的幕后工作中，才形成了强大的、全国范围的合力。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;国家的弄潮，决定 “弄潮” 的汇聚，带来步入新时代的突破。中国历史上，在面临危机关头时，不同时代的历史走向截然不同：宋朝后期，面临少数民族铁骑南下，朝廷一味求和，致使政权覆灭；新中国成立以来，在面对经济困难还是开拓新路的尝试中，国家总能成功突围。宋朝的覆灭，原因离不开国家并没有弄潮的意愿，自然无法凝聚全国上下的斗志，纵使有仁人志士挺身而出也最终无济于事；现在国家能取得如此成就，正是因为国家敢于挑战风浪，肩挑重担，尤其是在世界经历百年未有之大变局，国际关系风险横生的时代。国家是远比社会庞大的集体，唯有国家下定弄潮的决心，个人与社会的弄潮才能显示其力量，汇聚成推动历史的动力。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;个人、社会和国家的弄潮彼此相互依存，在超越现状与获得进步的道路上进步缺一不可。作为新时代的青年，我们需要意识到弄潮的进步作用，与风险搏斗，才能破除困境，走向新的境界。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;我读红楼梦之谜语人一般的行文风格&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#我读红楼梦之谜语人一般的行文风格&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 我读《红楼梦》之&lt;em&gt;谜语人一般的行文风格&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《红楼梦》一书之所以能跨越三个世纪的光阴而依旧被人们所熟知，其 “梦” 一般的文字功不可没。各种谐音、暗示和伏笔等贯穿全书，使得《红楼梦》如同神话一样，现实中对于贾府形形色色人物的描写、他们各自被预示的未来，乃至仙境中的隐秘之事水乳交融。《红楼梦》中有如此多的 “谜语” 和暗示，主要是因为曹雪芹使用了 “隐” 的写作方法。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于 “隐”，我们可以先简单归类一下。“隐” 在书中的使用以谐音、典故和 “离奇” 情节为主要方式：谐音有如 “甄士隐”“贾雨村”“英莲” 等人名的谐音；典故有书中人物点的戏剧，阅读的书籍等；“离奇” 情节主要指书中描写 “仙境” 的情节，如全部第一回和第五回中贾宝玉梦游太虚幻境。从种类颇多的 “隐” 来看，《红楼梦》被称作 “四大名著” 之首和曹雪芹以一本书就明冠天下都是自然而然的。关于 “隐” 的作用，大致有四点，在下文展开。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“隐” 预示未来&lt;br /&gt;
不可不说，这是 “隐” 最明显的作用了。关于这种作用，最典型的代表是第五回中金陵十二钗的判词和判曲了。尽管它们确实是来自曹雪芹的剧透，但这种朦朦胧胧的未知感也胜过你不知好歹的损友滔滔不绝的剧透。判词和判曲中，尤其悲凉和易懂的是最后一首 ——〔首尾・飞鸟各投林〕。“投林” 让人直接联想到 “树倒猢狲散”，进而领悟到这实际上是贾府的结局 —— 贾氏家族最后将彻底崩溃。当然，当时在太虚幻境里梦游的贾宝玉肯定想不到这是他们家族的未来，但读者们会带着这个冥冥中早已确定的结局阅读下去。在看着贾府中一个个人物登台退场时，读者难免心生悲哀和无奈之感 —— 因为读者们知道无论故事如何发展贾府都是消亡的结局。所以，预示未来的 “隐” 可以带给读者更深刻的阅读时情感体验。&lt;br /&gt;
“隐” 去的内容提高全书艺术价值&lt;br /&gt;
这里的 “艺术价值”，既指文字的美感，又指文字体现的精神思想。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从文字的角度，“隐” 的部分常以诗词的方式登场。这一点和许多中国古代小说一样，只要遇到人物登场或者事件发生就必有 “端的只见：” 和占满一页的诗。曹雪芹与众不同的是他将书中众人的结局通过谐音和拆字等方法融入到诗中，形成了判词和判曲，达到了虚实结合的效果。在第十七回中，曹雪芹写众人游大观园时也安排他们在各个景致前留下了诗歌、对联等，在渲染大观园别出心裁的设计时展现诗词和对联文化的魅力。曹雪芹还为林黛玉等人设计了 “海棠诗社”，对于塑造才女形象的作用自然不必赘述。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;从精神角度看，“隐” 展现了作者的精神追求。第一回的目的几乎就是这点，我们也能从中大篇幅的 “隐” 窥见。“甄士隐” 和 “贾雨村” 暗含 “真假” 和 “存隐”，这来自一些中国古代乃至印度佛教的理念，但由于我觉悟不够所以省略具体诠释。跛足道人的《好了歌》更加体现了曹雪芹对于功名的态度：人们建功立业、发财致富、贪恋妻妾、顾念儿孙都是被情欲蒙蔽，不可取。而这也是全书的核心之一，由此我们也可以得出 “隐” 的另一个含义……&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“隐” 展现作者的倒影&lt;br /&gt;
文学家写书，多多少少都会在书中影射自己。而在《红楼梦》中，整部书都是在 “真事隐” 的前提下展开的，“真事” 指的什么自然不言而喻 —— 是曹雪芹家道中落前的生活。身为江南织造之家的公子，他在江南享受了荣华富贵，甚至乾隆皇帝南巡都在他们府中落脚。从一方面来说，这些上流社会的生活时曹雪芹接触了大量的知识，他出神入化的服饰描写就可以证明。另一方面，他也见识了上流社会的腐朽，在被抄家后他于是反思这一切的开端，于是就有了警醒世人的《红楼梦》。从某种程度上说，《红楼梦》中贾府正是曹府。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;总之&lt;br /&gt;
 “隐” 成就了《红楼梦》，为读者展开了一个与书平行的世界，使曹雪芹自己的倒影荡漾在读者的脑海中。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;comments-on-fence-or-ambulance&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#comments-on-fence-or-ambulance&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Comments on &amp;quot;Fence or ambulance&amp;quot;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the fact that this classical poem was written approximately 130 years ago, the discussion of whether construct a fence or assemble a fleet of ambulances down in that hypothetical valley continued to this day. As a part of the content itself, people’s opinions towards the two options were mentioned: some of them were advocates of the ambulance, as it seemed straightforward enough to those people; some, however, believed the fence is better as it prevented any further tragedies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In my point of view, same with the author, a fence is certainly better than an ambulance. It can be explained through multiple aspects, and I’m in favor of these two: cost and effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of cost, the fence is certainly a lot cheaper in different ways. Though ambulances are indeed flexible, it is widely acknowledged that operating them requires a fortune: not just the cost of vehicles, but also expenses of medical instruments as well as labor cost should be added. For the fence, it only requires the initial installation cost and regular maintenance. Nevertheless, both plans are capable of saving lives, yet at different costs, and it is apparent to judge which is more economic. In our school lives, time is what matters the most, and time cost of different learning styles is visible. Going through different subjects altogether at the end of the month require several days and even a whole week, yet completing revision tasks daily only takes minutes. I’m uncertain about others’ choices, but I’m going to build my “fence” day by day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Referring to effect, the fence reaches a far more realistic outcome. Ambulances evidently rescue people that are already in danger, and dying in some cases might be inevitable, as it takes time for the ambulance to arrive, which means they cannot save all lives or have a better result. On the other hand, fences prevent people from standing close to the cliff, thus nobody would fall. Surly the fence can save all lives quickly and with no further matters to worry. Similar in our lives, stopping the cause of problems is a lot convenient than repairing consequences. It is always a better option to improve our studies by going through textbooks and mistakes daily than do a lot of exercises after countless mistakes. The first way can stop most problems in the future, yet the latter only tackles with the current situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To sum up, the fence option is more appealing than ambulances, as it can reach a better outcome with relatively little effort. Having said that, it is still uneasy to build a fence of your own, owing to the fact that fences require the persistence of yourself. Nevertheless, fences stand out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-3/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.3|《枪炮、病菌和钢铁（Guns, Germs and Steel）》读后感</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-3/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2023 22:52:35 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;注：这还是 STY 的暑假作业之一，主要是七月三稿想不出来写什么，干脆拿着个先占个位置，后面再去补一个好东西（遥遥无期啊 www）&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note default&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;真的，作业清单上说是 800 字就行，结果 STY 直接写了 2692 才收住&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;人类社会的命运以环境的视角&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#人类社会的命运以环境的视角&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 人类社会的命运，以环境的视角&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;——《枪炮、病菌和钢铁（Guns, Germs and Steel）》读后感&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 不管是小学品德和社会课，还是初中的历史、道德与法治乃至地理学科，到高中的思想政治，我们或多或少都对人类如何从畏惧黑夜的直立生物变成占领全球的物种的过程有个基本的理解。但是很重要的一点是，我们在对这些历史的学习中，是将人类作为一个整体而言的，明显忽略了人类种群内部的差异性 —— 社会的不同。而对于人类不同社会的理解，有一本书给了我极大的震撼，就是贾雷德・戴蒙得的作品《枪炮，钢铁和病菌》。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;首先，虽然我知道不能通过书名评价一本书，但不得不说这本书的标题是多么引人注目。英文原名 Guns, Germs and Steel 这三个毫无关系的词语直接点出了作者认为的人类社会中最具侵略性的力量，而且中文版由此采取的直译方式也十分惊艳，充分展现了作者对于人类社会的深刻认识。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;全书以一个问题串连起。但是这里选取的问题并非古希腊哲学家的思考抑或是某个学者的千古一问，而是 1972 年新几内亚岛上的政治人物亚力在碰巧遇到研究鸟类时的贾雷德时提出的疑问：“为什么白人制造出这么多货物，再运来这里？为什么我们黑人没搞出什么名堂？”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;确实，这个问题普遍存在，我们都清楚西欧和北美是发达国家聚集的地区，而亚洲非洲等地的经济情况在以上两个地域前显得寒酸。但作者不得不承认这是一个 “看来简单，却难以回答” 的问题，因为我们早已习惯于这一差距。25 年后，贾雷德用这本书试图向读者解答亚力的疑问。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;对于亚力的疑问，答案看似是不同人种的优缺点，但是作者否决了这一观点。作为人类历史和人类社会活化石的一片天地，新几内亚岛让贾雷德见识了不少当地土著部落，就比如相互敌视的新几内亚高地人和低地人、彪悍的法玉人和被他们吓坏了的奇里奇里人。作者本身是美国人，对白人肯定有普遍的认知，再加上他多年来与新几内亚当地人的交流，他最后认为这些在 “石器时代” 生活的黑人的智力非但不会比 “工业社会” 中的白人逊色，甚至还可能强于他们。我们坚决反对种族歧视，而贾雷德正为此找到了有力的证据。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;那么为什么新几内亚岛上黑人和欧美的白人发展水平天差地别呢？我总结出作者认为其背后的原因是四类环境差异。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第一类是自然资源方面的差异，主要体现在自然界中可驯化的动植物资源。很明显，这些资源越多，可供养的人口就越多。为论证此部分，作者通过植物学知识分析了大种子植物分布对人类分布的关系，通过对类似 “肥沃新月” 等早期农业区的分析介绍了动植物资源组成的 “生物包（biological package）” 对文明的产生的重要性。全书整个第二部分即为食物生产的兴起与扩散，相关的分析与资料的选取十分科学，尤其是作者通过一个个表格将通常情况下动辄几页纸的抽象论述总结出植物与人类发展的关联。而且，作者也提出稠密的人口会促进的病菌的演化，从而增强此地人群的抵抗力的观点。这是一个难以置信的结论，但事实正是如此，例如非洲中部的疟疾促使当地科洛桑人等部落进化出特殊造型的红细胞，从而减少疟原虫入侵的可能。由此可见，自然资源更加丰富的西欧文明得以迅速发展，而气候湿热、雨林环境恶劣的新几内亚岛的文明发展水平明显更低。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第二类是气候和环境方面的差异，主要体现在影响农业传播的自然条件。欧亚大陆文明区的纬度差距不大，从中国到西欧以及返程上的农作物得以在两个地区正常生长，同时自然条件的不同也可以促进每一代植物的变异，丰富自然资源，作用于上一段中提到的第一类差异，促进欧亚大陆上文化的发展。从今天的视角我们也能验证这一观点：从东亚的中日韩三国，到西欧伊比利亚半岛，不论沿途的国家的经济发展水平如何，都融合了国际社会，同时国内的历史也能上溯至极远的年代。而新几内亚岛上的热带雨林气候难以使岛内的农作物资源相互交流，更不用说来自外界的作物了。所以，农业的快速传播是欧亚大陆得以快速发展的重要原因，而新几内亚岛文明发展落后也有一部分原因归于农业传播缓慢。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第三类是影响技术洲际传播的因素，主要体现在地理差异。这里，作者介绍了 “大陆轴线” 的理论。为了解释大陆轴线的特点，以及大陆轴线如何影响了人类社会，我们需要来一点地理知识。地球绕太阳公转，同时自转。假如我们拿着地球仪模拟此过程，我们能清晰地看出一个事实：纬度相同的地区，不管经度如何变化，自然环境多少有相似之处，因为这些地区接受阳光的情况大致相同，只是时间不同；经度相同的地区只要纬度发生变化，自然环境就会发生极大的变化，因为这些地区接受阳光的情况不会一致。由此可见，如果大陆轴线沿着纬线南北展开，则轴线上的自然环节千差万别；而假如大陆轴线沿着纬线东西展开，则轴线上的自然环境总会有些相似之处。而适应了一个特定自然环境的人类自然在类似的环境中更轻松地跋涉，这也使东西展开的大陆轴线能让技术更快传播，而南北向的大陆轴线反而会阻碍技术传播。欧亚大陆的大陆轴线大致沿东西方向从中国直通伊比利亚半岛，而至于新几内亚所在的大洋洲甚至…… 没有明显的大陆轴线，导致技术传播向哪个方向都不甚容易。总之，以大陆轴线为主的地理差异延缓了新几内亚岛的文化发展。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第四类是各大洲环境与创新水平的关系，体现在人口总数与大陆面积。关于人口因素，有一个简单的例子：欧亚大陆有发达国家日本，也有近几十年来追赶上的中国和韩国，这三个人口大国中涌现出了数不胜数的发明家与探索者，不管是哪个时代；而至于大洋洲群岛，每个群岛人口可能只有万余人，连人口总数都远少于东亚三国，自然这里诞生科学家的概率更低。对于中日韩的例子来说，更多的创新者会激发三国间的竞争，带来更多科技创新。至于大陆面积对于文化发展的影响，欧洲是更好的例子。欧洲从来没有统一过，而欧洲面积较小，土地资源有限，各个国家之间争夺资源，导致更多战争发生，同时战争催化科学进步，例如为军队研发武器时的伽利略研究出了自由落体理论。但这是建立在欧洲本身动植物资源丰富的基础上的，新几内亚岛本身的资源不足以使它在土地资源受限时反而建立辉煌的文明。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;在分析出这四个结论后，我感到自己对于 “我们” 的认知更加深入了。通过作者贾雷德的文笔，我意识到人类的一举一动都有自然的作用，不管是人类的产生、人类的迁移、人类文明的扩展乃至如今人类社会的未来。作为优秀的生物学家，贾雷德从环境的视角审视了 1.3 万年的岁月，尝试着为 40 多年前新几内亚岛上的政治家亚力解释人类社会的命运。尽管他也不完全支持所谓的 “环境决定论”，但他通过贯通始终的分析框架，为我们展示了人类社会差异的一种解释。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“因此我很乐观，人类社会的历史可以当作科学来研究，就像研究恐龙一样。&lt;br /&gt;
我们的收获对当今的社会有益，&lt;br /&gt;
因为我们明白了什么塑造了现代世界，&lt;br /&gt;
什么又可能塑造我们的未来”&lt;br /&gt;
——《枪炮、病菌和钢铁》收场白&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-2/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.2|《地球的力量》观后感</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeistuOrchestra%20vol-2/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:49:17 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;注：这是 STY 的暑假作业之一，主要是七月二稿想不出来写什么，干脆拿着个先占个位置，后面再去补一个好东西&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;蓝色惑星的不羁搏动&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#蓝色惑星的不羁搏动&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; 蓝色惑星的不羁搏动&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;——《地球的力量》观后感&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;more&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;说到地球的力量，2023 年的人类最直观的感受就是极端天气频发与反常高温，在高温预警中北半球又战战兢兢地过着一个又一个难熬的夏日。现在，全球变暖的效果已经如此明显，21 世纪 10 年代以来几乎每个半球的夏天里都会传出对应极点超过 20-30 摄氏度的新闻，崩塌的冰川也几乎无法挽回，而人类已经开始真正见证地球紊乱时的失控力量 —— 温室气体浓度升高会影响整个生物圈。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;而在这个北京 40 多年来最热的一个夏天里，我观看了地理老师推荐的纪录片《地球的力量》，一部近 16 年前的经典作品。尽管片中部分数据和事实已经过时，但整部纪录片带来的对自然地理和地球的理解是更为可贵的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;纪录片着眼于那些地球上的 “无形力量”。火山、大气、冰川、海洋，这些是编导眼中的地球之力。从埃塞俄比亚阿法州尔塔阿雷火山永不融化的熔岩湖到新西兰南岛南阿尔卑斯山，第一集讲述了炽热的地核如何推动了生命的产生；从一代代航空先驱勇探上层大气，到遍布世界的叠层石制造氧气，第二集揭示了曾经充满一氧化碳和甲烷的大气如何成为生命的天地的原因；从阿拉斯加狭地的冰河遗址到挪威破碎的峡湾，第三集展示了看似脆弱的冰是如何塑造了世界的外貌；从周游世界的塑料鸭子，到摧毁世界 90% 生命的二叠纪大灭绝，第四集分析了海洋除了支持水生生命外还有多少显著的作用：构建世界的几种力量在四个角度中展示地淋漓尽致。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;跟随镜头和特效，我对地球的认知更加深刻。当我们把地球当成家园、当做人类一展宏图的白纸时，我们更应该认识到地球本身的生命性。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第一个认知，是对地球活力的理解。在大多数时候，地球在我们眼中充当着仅仅是 “大地” 的角色，而我们也应该牢记地球也是生命。尔塔阿雷火山口中的熔岩不仅每时每刻都在喷涌，而且熔岩湖上方冷却成的黑色硬壳也随着地球自转而旋转；冰岛的火山除了带来大量廉价的地热能以外还塑造这个岛屿国家的地貌，凭空造出一座耸立的岛屿，甚至冰岛本身就是坐落在一座直通地幔的熔岩柱而上。与此同时，火星由于火山活动的停止而成为了 “死” 行星；木卫二全球性海洋下的火山持续喷发冰水混合物却使其保持活力，甚至可能孕育生命。可见地球确实是充满生机与活力的，同时这份生机与活力对于全地球的生命是如此重要。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第二个认知，是对地球体系的理解。现在，我国倡导人类命运共同体的建设，在古代也有连接东西方的丝绸之路与联系西欧与南北美洲的新航路，但这些远没有地球自然形成的地区间联系迷人。纪录片中一个令人印象深刻的部分是是撒哈拉沙漠的狂风卷起富含矿物质的沙土，无机盐顺着风向漂洋过海渡过中大西洋，最终落到亚马逊雨。更重要的是 —— 它们是这片雨林的最大营养来源。相似的故事还有很多，例如刚果河 “消失” 的三角洲事实上为大西洋底的海洋生物提供了营养。总之，地球的整体性塑造了地球的生命性，正如动植物个体是器官的整体。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;第三个认知，是对地球力量的理解。地球的力量，仅仅是在全片的体现 “火山、大气、冰川、海洋” 也并非像核裂变一样具有毁天灭地的力量。而它们却真实地改造了地球。纪录片也揭示了这些力量的来源。以海洋为例，海洋看似只是咸水的集合体，却引发了二叠纪末期的生物大灭绝。事实上海洋内至关重要的是洋流，因为洋流串连了全世界的所有海洋。洋流依赖于热水与冷水的对流，但二叠纪末期由于气候变暖水域之间的温度差已经开始缩小，导致洋流逐渐停止，使地球的海水成为了一潭全球范围的死水塘，引发海洋物种的灭绝。同时气候变暖也因为海水升温而继续，导致陆地上蒸发量增大，大部分陆地生物也难逃灭绝的命运。所以，地球的力量来源于各个要素的因果关系，这也是人类要尽力在 21 世纪 20 年代以后控制的。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;《地球的力量》无疑对于自然地理的理解有独特的价值，尤其是对于气候变暖、海平面上升，出现各种环境挑战与伴生问题的现在。这部纪录片通过对地球力量的剖析，为我们理解地球，保护地球起到了积极的作用。随着一项项环境议定书的批准，各国环境政策的出台，我们这颗有着不羁力量的蓝色行星应当会持续搏动下去。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeitsuOrchestra%20vol-5/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.5| STY奇文共赏之扯淡英语作业</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeitsuOrchestra%20vol-5/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <category>水水水</category>
            <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 10:49:17 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;这个是老师留的作业，要求是写一个和春节有关系的文段。看过了学长的迷之示例（2100 年春节他们家去莫斯科玩，不小心引起了火灾，最后还被活了一百多年的普京提溜走了。普京人还怪好的，给他们做饺子，结果吃饺子的时候普京自己噎④了）后我们组也要整一个！&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was Spring Festival of year 2100, I got together with my family and went to Mars for the special holiday. We highly valued this trip, as my family can reunite on such a marvelous world. Our spaceship was super cutting-edge, therefore we arrived in less than a day. After we landed on mars, we immediately realized that we had landed at the incorrect Mars station, which was a miserable thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Luckily, a group of Chinese scientists brought us back. They showed their hospitality by giving us some Mars delicacy —— Mars fish. As we know, fish carries unique meanings in Chinese culture, and it was amazing to see that Chinese people still keep and practise the original customs. While we were cooking the fish to make dumplings, we noticed the smell of iron, but we didn’t pay attention. In the end, we found that the fish was full of iron (III) oxide, a common mineral on Mars, but it was too late as we had finished it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, a guy called Elon Musk, who owned SpaceX, decided to aid us. He provided us some basic medicine and an even better reunion dinner! To get us fully recovered, Elon lent us his Starship to send us back home, but it exploded again and lit up the Martian night sky. Nevertheless, we took the escape pod and evacuated in time. A Chinese spaceship found us and we boarded it. We talked about the old times and shared views about Mars tourism with the crew on the way back. What an exhilarating Spring Festival!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <guid isPermalink="true">https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeitsuOrchestra%20vol-1/</guid>
            <title>Ameitsu Orchestra vol.1 | Descending Digital Dark Ages</title>
            <link>https://ameitsu.github.io/Ameitsu-Orchestra/ameitsu-orchestra/AmeitsuOrchestra%20vol-1/</link>
            <category>原创</category>
            <category>Ameitsu Orchestra</category>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 22:21:00 +0800</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[ &lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/painting.digitaldarkages.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;painting.digitaldarkages.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span id=&#34;more&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;note info&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Congratulations! This is the first post of Ameitsu Orchestra, and the first long, proper article posted by STY&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imagine this&lt;/strong&gt;: you are writing stuff on your personal blog site, then just out of a sudden you realized &lt;strong&gt;ALL PICTURES IN YOUR IMAGE HOST&lt;/strong&gt; went 404. There is only one possible reason: the image host that you have used now has a broken server, and clearly it will not be fixed until the end of the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is surely frightening enough, isn’t it? While you are feeling glad that it is just an invented story, but that is &lt;ins&gt;exactly what happened&lt;/ins&gt; to this site earlier in June. While I flickered through the local files, busy re-uploading pictures and rewriting links, I really wondered the reason why on earth something like that could ever happen &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34; title=&#34;你知道得太多了&#34;&gt;in the age that some artificial intelligences became Yanderes as they chat with humans.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;similar-question-closer-to-life&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#similar-question-closer-to-life&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Similar Question Closer To Life&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certainly the broken-image-host scenario is 100% fictional in most people’s lives, similar problems do occur—well, even more frustrating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To have a better picture about the problem, here are 3 non-fiction cases. To make it easier to read, the sensitive information has been replaced with characters and contents from the Asano Monokoto series.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A.	Natsuki san has just got a &lt;mark&gt;R-18 yuri illustration&lt;/mark&gt; from a friend of him, and he certainly wants to take a peek at other works by the same artist. He then opened the trending, hi-tech Ameitsu Netbox browser to search it via the picture AI. Eventually he discovered the link to the account of the original creator of the picture, and tragedy happened——due to the non-compatible api settings of both sites and anti-spider protocols, only a fearsome 404 page loaded out. Now, the city of Lashak has one more sad boy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;B.	Yukika chan picked up a smart-looking camera in her bedroom, and she obviously wants to recover the vulnerable data as it recorded the &lt;mark&gt;happy moments&lt;/mark&gt; that Shenyu senpai spent with her. To fill the hungry stomach of the battery module, Yukika looked everywhere for a recharge line. It is a misery for her to realize that no recharge line fits every device, and it is too late to know that not everything is sold all-year-round.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C.	Scotia is checking the updates of a &lt;mark&gt;currently developing software&lt;/mark&gt; of her team via a SVM tool. The joy of appreciating teamwork soon became the frustration that she could not tell what new functions have been edited. What’s more, corrupted characters were everywhere, literally nothing human-readable was shown on the dashboard of the IDE. Therefore, a group of passionate IT people had to give up their precious weekend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the 3 cases, we surely can understand the devastating effect of “lost information”. Although hard to imagine, the digitalized modern human society suffers from those 404 exceptions. Of course humanity will not vanish if a file cannot be found, but—it is just too annoying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone has encountered those unfortunate moments of their homework assignments gone away without a trace, therefore nobody ever wants cyber resources to disappear like those awful pieces of paper material in daily lives, yet lost information makes the cyberspace so close to reality. That is what we call &lt;ins&gt;Digital Dark Ages&lt;/ins&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/R-C-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;R-C-1.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-on-earth-is-a-dark-age&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-on-earth-is-a-dark-age&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; What On Earth Is a Dark Age&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since it is named as “Digital Dark Ages”, we should be certain about what “Dark Ages” mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term Dark Age we are talking about here is exactly the &lt;ins&gt;Dark Ages&lt;/ins&gt; period in European history, a “dark” time during the medieval, before the Renaissance. It is commonly recognized that this period saw little scientific and cultural advancement, yet is challenged by scholars and historians present day, as new evidence of rich technological development is being discovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, we are certainly not in an awful history class, it is useless to pay attention to all these controversies. Meanwhile, the “classical” character of this nine centuries is the lack of records, and that is the key to the new term, Digital Dark Ages. Instead of archives being destroyed or disappeared, the modern version of dark ages transferred the object of losing to &lt;ins&gt;limitless and precious digital records.&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/R-C-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;R-C-1.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;digital-dark-ages&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#digital-dark-ages&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Digital Dark Ages&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, we can truly understand the main concept of this article. Instead of archives being destroyed or disappeared, the modern version of dark ages transferred the object of losing to limitless and precious digital records.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, of course humanity has just stepped into the wide world of web, yet the Digital Dark Ages has already begun decades ago—not too long after we became digital.&lt;ins&gt;Elspeth Olson&lt;/ins&gt;at University of Nevada, Reno, has a story to tell.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2020, while processing historic school files, Elspeth encountered a floppy disk, then followed their procedure for sending legacy media and digital storage to Digital Services for file extraction. Not too surprisingly, the files were in a version of Microsoft Word from the late 1990s, and initially showed on their screens as complete gibberish. Current computers could not read the files. Another researcher, Nathan Gerth, and his team in the library’s Digital Services department were able to recover the data and reconstruct the documents, but being able to do so is not guaranteed. They are lucky to have a department focused on the challenges of digitization and preserving born-digital materials, although the thing that made them working day and night is just a floppy disc manufactured a bit over 20 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From the case, it is clear to understand the fact that digital dark ages is totally not a legendary issue like the “millennium worm” that happens once for a lifetime and potentially could destruct human internet world, digital dark ages happen silently and not so soon after we eventually got computers into domestic gadgets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/otm-darkage.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;otm-darkage.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Digital dark ages has one &lt;ins&gt;internal cause&lt;/ins&gt;: information and its compatible reading method gradually become unmatched. Digital files are highly prone to degradation and data loss, especially with repeated transference to new storage and retrieval systems, in other words, computers and portable devices of different companies using various operating systems. Due to the slight difference between generations of the same device and the vast split among all types of electronic devices, information loss is inevitable, no matter the file became unable to open, being disappeared like your TV remote control or turned into a page of corrupted characters just like high school math tests. Every time you change your computer or upgrade the operating system, you risk data loss. We’ve all felt that stomach-clenching fear when a file won’t open or seems to have vanished.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take STY as an example. STY preserved literally everything since grade 1, and including all those Powerpoint presentations. 10 years after the first day of primary school, many of the earliest files  either has misplaced content or missing words. It seems like IT has devolved, yet the truth is that technology has greatly advanced. Microsoft Powerpoint evolved from a odd bracket with azure-transparent backgrounds to a contemporary red-and-white design, and so as the functions. From the first glimpse our lives could be greatly improved by those software innovations, however it can possibly kill the past as not all old files adapt to the new system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;ins&gt;Dead file format&lt;/ins&gt; also proves a problem. Without sufficient maintaining, files dedicated to one specific application may be in severe danger. Imagine one day Adobe Photoshop died, and you are sure to lose those then-useless .psd files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a word, making &lt;ins&gt;files not suited&lt;/ins&gt;with corresponding methods of retrieval and processing methods makes our cyberspace rotten from within.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;how-we-made-it-a-reality&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#how-we-made-it-a-reality&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; How we made it a reality?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unquestionably, nobody wants to make their score lower on the fact that they wrote something on their math test that is certainly incorrect. Similarly, none of us wish for lost documents, despite the fact that digital dark age is largely a not-intended mistake. The core reason is that, we have not foreseen the fact that the digitalized human society would appear in only several decades after the first personal computer came to view, and at the time we became conscious of the great momentousness of the cyberspace, we are just too late. Yes, that is a classical &lt;span class=&#34;spoiler&#34; title=&#34;你知道得太多了&#34;&gt;high-EQ&lt;/span&gt; expression of Ameitsu Cyberpark, however assuredly we should understand the external—or ours—responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-and-me&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#you-and-me&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; You and me&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users generate information. Obviously that’s a truth, yet we users are the first to face the catastrophic effect of digital dark ages. It all begins with the fact that users seldom aware the value of historic archives. Technically, documents are stored locally on our electronic devices, thus not everyone has enough space on their disk, therefore old files tend to give way to newer files. The common method of displacing files is either remove it forever by throwing it in the recycle bin, or copy them to a memory stick. In terms of the first option, one delete means those lost content will never be recovered again, which is uncomplicated to understand. For the second way, even your 128GB memory stick looks so robust, even so nobody is certain about whether you have the possibility of passing it down to your grandkids or not. There is something for sure: human technology evolves faster than you backup and checking files. Hence &lt;ins&gt;making files means files in danger&lt;/ins&gt;, quite thrilling though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platforms-whatever-they-do&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#platforms-whatever-they-do&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Platforms, whatever they do&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Files and information are somehow stored on a platform, and that’s exactly the place where digital dark age embodies. As far as STY concerned, information loss happens in these forms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;External: ++retrieval system and storage method do not match. ++&lt;br /&gt;
Sounds geeky though, but what we are talking is just what 404 response mean. The retrieval system cannot locate or read the designated resource, so a “File Not Found” response is raised. The main reason is that api settings and spider protocols have exceptions. Due to the fact that most retrieval systems are simply browsers, therefore the result of this scenario is devastating. Apis are not essentially same from platform to platform, as a result, literally no files are universally compatible with their retrieval systems , even though the exactly same program running on various operating systems. In the end, we have information loss.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internal: &lt;ins&gt;the invisible wall between platforms&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
There is no doubt that internet connected humanity. Anyway, we cannot say the internet is really inter-connected. Nowadays, barriers between information providers are even more apparent. As an example, a number of links cannot be shown or opened correctly in specific social networks, just because the corresponding companies are commercial rivals.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the distrust between platforms, information loss can occur within the same platform. To give way to new functions, older ones need to be removed. Yes, sounds nothing strange, but what would you feel if those old functions stored all of your precious photographs? The upgrade of services not only brings new experiences, but also deepen the digital dark ages&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/Screen-Shot-2015-02-15-at-12.29.07-PM.webp&#34; alt=&#34;Screen-Shot-2015-02-15-at-12.29.07-PM.webp&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;an-inevitable-consequence&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#an-inevitable-consequence&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; An Inevitable Consequence&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike in previous decades, no physical record exists these days for much of the digital material we own. Consequently, the number one crisis digital dark ages might bring is ++loss of detailed information of our society.+&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We may one day know less about the early 21st century than we do about the early 20th century,” says &lt;ins&gt;Rick West&lt;/ins&gt;, who manages data at Google. “The early 20th century is still largely based on things like paper and film formats that are still accessible to a large extent; whereas, much of what we&#39;re doing now — the things we&#39;re putting into the cloud, our digital content — is born digital. It&#39;s not something that we translated from an analog container into a digital container, but, in fact, it is born, and now increasingly dies, as digital content, without any kind of analog counterpart.” It is always a terrifying story if we imagine the archaeologists of the 22nd century may deeply rely on phone craps rather than old webpages to rebuild their understanding of the 21st century world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other experts call the 21st century an ++“informational black hole,” ++because the digital information we are creating right now may not be readable by machines and software programs of the future. All that data, they worry — our century’s digital history — is at risk of never being recoverable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The section above is only 221 words long, but STY assumes you can fully understand the disastrous result of the digital dark ages. Imagine 21st century humans, that has conquered the earth and its vicinage , sent probes to all solar system planets may “disappear” as few digital evidences remain……&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/R-C.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;R-C.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-on-earth-can-we-do&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#what-on-earth-can-we-do&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; What On Earth Can We Do&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like mathematics is built on ultra-simple-and-straightforward theorems, we need something &lt;ins&gt;low-tech&lt;/ins&gt; to conserve our cyber world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, many of the world’s largest companies and data-based enterprises still rely on an old storage medium: &lt;mark&gt;magnetic tape&lt;/mark&gt;. In 1952, IBM introduced the first magnetic tape data storage system, ushering in the modern era of electronic computing. An early tape unit could hold about 2.3 megabytes per reel on two tapes. In the modern ages, those antique tapes are still being used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lauren Young is Science Friday&#39;s web producer and the lead reporter on a three-part series called &amp;quot;File Not Found&amp;quot; that explores issues of data storage (and loss) of all kinds. A single cartridge of today’s magnetic tape can hold hundreds of terabytes of data, the equivalent to hundreds of millions of books, Young says. “This past summer, IBM increased the amount a cartridge can hold to 330 terabytes, which is 330,000 gigabytes per cartridge. Big companies like Google and particle physics labs like Fermilab all have massive libraries of tape with thousands and thousands of cartridges.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In many cases, magnetic tape is the backup to the backup. This, too, can present problems, in the form of evolving magnetic formats and a phenomenon known as &amp;quot;bit rot.&amp;quot; Over time, the digital information on tape, and in other digital formats, can decay or degrade if it is not stored properly or is subjected to other adverse conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, magnetic tapes are not 100% reliable. Kari Kraus, an associate professor in the College of Information Studies at the University of Maryland in College Park and who helps run a project that rescues and resurrects digital relics, including video games and virtual worlds, knows about bit rot, and its close relative &amp;quot;software rot,&amp;quot; in which old files, games and other data becomes unusable because no format exists to read and reproduce the information.“Different storage media have different lifespans,” Kraus says. “In our project, we worked a lot with magnetic media like floppy disks and those only have a lifespan of, say, 10 to 14 years. Optical media like DVDs and CD-ROM, I believe have even less. It is going to be a problem across different storage media.”&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img data-src=&#34;https://cdnjson.com/images/2023/08/11/era-oscura-digital-digital-dark-age.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;era-oscura-digital-digital-dark-age.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Besides grandparent-style technologies, fancier ones are also considered. Some researchers see hope in one of the newest technologies: &lt;mark&gt;DNA storage&lt;/mark&gt;. “Basically, researchers have found a way to store data onto DNA, which is a billion-year-old molecule that can store the essence of life,” Young explains. “It&#39;s pretty incredible that they can do that. It&#39;s all synthetically made; it’s not genomic DNA.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By utilizing DNA , storage capacity can be measured in petabytes; that is, millions of gigabytes. Single gram of DNA could, in principle, store every bit of datum ever recorded by humans in a container about the size and weight of a couple of pickup trucks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from practicing some “proper solutions”, &lt;mark&gt;cruder methods&lt;/mark&gt; are still worth a try. LOCKSS, which stands for Lots Of Copies Keeps Stuff Safe, is one of them. By all means, scan your family photographs, have virtual libraries and albums, and create digital data in all forms. Have digital backups run automatically and store in the cloud or to an external hard drive. For the stuff that’s really important, though, print out hard copies. They last longer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Universities, scientific institutions and similar entities embrace knowledge than the rest. And we are glad to see that more &lt;mark&gt;databases&lt;/mark&gt; are completed in university libraries globally. Take Nevada University that we have mentioned as an example. During each academic year, the libraries welcomes more than 1.2 million visitors across its network of three libraries: the Mathewson-IGT Knowledge Center, the DeLaMare Science and Engineering Library and the Savitt Medical Library. Visitors checked-out more than 90,000 items and completed more than 2 million database searches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Moreover, even without innovation, &lt;mark&gt;opensource projects&lt;/mark&gt; can significantly help save digital records. Microsoft’s Open XML is dedicated in converting Word and Powerpoint files into this open format, so that the risk of file loss can be greatly reduced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;lastly&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#lastly&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; Lastly&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So far, as we can all see, the digital dark age is developing. Moreover, it seems that few is done to this field, comparing the effect of it. It is sure that new information is kept being produced, nevertheless the past has the same importance. Anyway, we see a twilight. It has been proved that both low-tech applications and state-of-the-art developments can help save the precious human internet world. But what’s more, we need &lt;ins&gt;those who are determined to brighten the twilight.&lt;/ins&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;anchor&#34; href=&#34;#references&#34;&gt;#&lt;/a&gt; References&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🔴1.	&lt;a href=&#34;https://ameitsu.github.io&#34;&gt;https://ameitsu.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;🟠2.	&lt;span class=&#34;exturl&#34; data-url=&#34;aHR0cHM6Ly9zdHVkeS5jb20vYWNhZGVteS9sZXNzb24vdGhlLWRhcmstYWdlcy1kZWZpbml0aW9uLWhpc3RvcnktdGltZWxpbmUuaHRtbA==&#34;&gt;https://study.com/academy/lesson/the-dark-ages-definition-history-timeline.html&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
🟡3.	&lt;span class=&#34;exturl&#34; data-url=&#34;aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuaGlzdG9yeWhpdC5jb20vd2h5LXdlcmUtdGhlLWVhcmx5LW1pZGRsZS1hZ2VzLWNhbGxlZC10aGUtZGFyay1hZ2VzLw==&#34;&gt;https://www.historyhit.com/why-were-the-early-middle-ages-called-the-dark-ages/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
🟢4.	&lt;span class=&#34;exturl&#34; data-url=&#34;aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cudW5yLmVkdS9uZXZhZGEtdG9kYXkvbmV3cy8yMDIyL2xpYnJhcmllcy1kaWdpdGFsLWRhcmstYWdlcw==&#34;&gt;https://www.unr.edu/nevada-today/news/2022/libraries-digital-dark-ages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
🔵5.	&lt;span class=&#34;exturl&#34; data-url=&#34;aHR0cHM6Ly90aGV3b3JsZC5vcmcvc3Rvcmllcy8yMDE4LTAxLTAxL3NjaWVudGlzdHMtd2Fybi13ZS1tYXktYmUtY3JlYXRpbmctZGlnaXRhbC1kYXJrLWFnZQ==&#34;&gt;https://theworld.org/stories/2018-01-01/scientists-warn-we-may-be-creating-digital-dark-age&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
🟣6.	&lt;span class=&#34;exturl&#34; data-url=&#34;aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cud2lraXdhbmQuY29tL2VuL0RpZ2l0YWxfZGFya19hZ2U=&#34;&gt;https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Digital_dark_age&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
🟤7.	&lt;span class=&#34;exturl&#34; data-url=&#34;aHR0cHM6Ly93d3cuYnJpdGFubmljYS5jb20vZXZlbnQvRGFyay1BZ2Vz&#34;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/event/Dark-Ages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;link rel=&#34;stylesheet&#34; href=&#34;/css/spoiler.css&#34; type=&#34;text/css&#34;&gt;&lt;script src=&#34;/js/spoiler.js&#34; type=&#34;text/javascript&#34; async&gt;&lt;/script&gt; ]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>
